Brett Burdick

Junior Web Developer

Atlanta, Georgia burdickbrett@outlook.com (770) 870-0668 brettburdick.com github.com/brett-b linkedin.com/in/brettdb

Recent Projects

speakEASY

11.2016

A full-stack chat community web app built with a geo-graphical interface, which allows the user to see speakeasy locations near their current location or the location sent from other users. The map markers also provide information for each location as well as a link to direct them into a private chat room. While providing a custom map, the most challenging process in development was researching locations so I could write the JSON for every speakeasy, as this, was not in the Google Maps API. I built a RESTful API connected to MongoDB to persist data, as well as hold the JSON for each speakeasy. Being the only developer in the creation of this app provided me with new challenges, which I enjoyed being able to tackle unassisted, and gain the personal experience.

Brew.place

08.2016

A responsive SPA where users can research beer throughout local breweries, as wells as bookmark their favorite beer into local storage. Using the AngularJS framework together with Bootstrap, allows for a clean layout, accessible on any device. The most challenging hurdled with this project was working with an API that was not CORS compliant. Future goals will be to implement a proxy server to request JSON more effectively.

Education

Immersive Full-Stack Web Development ALP – DigitalCrafts (Atlanta Campus)

07.2016 - 11.2016

Dedicated over 665 classroom-hours covering both client-side and server-side web development. Spanning 16 continuous weeks, the curriculum detailed HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, including an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like AngularJS and jQuery. Server based technology training was based around both the MEAN stack and Python. Academics were constantly reinforced with daily exercises and ongoing projects that instilled the importance of agile development and stressed the importance of version control and continuous integration. UI/UX design elective brought together the methodologies of research with industry design tools such as Sketch, Photoshop, and InVision to get a project from a wireframe to working prototype.

Computer Networking/Cryptography/Switching Systems - Community College of the Air Force

2000 - 2001

1171 hours of training with certification in:

- Electronic Principles –
- E3AQR2E231
- Data Processor/Display System Maintenance J4ASF2E2X1-037
- Computer Networking and Switching Systems E3ABR2E231

Work Experience

Server – Chops Lobster Bar – Atlanta, Georgia – (404) 262-2675

2015 – present

Delivered first-class customer service working in a high-volume premier steakhouse.

Corporate Training Manager – Ray's Restaurants – Sandy Springs, Georgia – (770) 955-1187

2008 - 2015

Created and implemented a web-based training course on <u>Schoox</u> to be used company-wide (05.2014). Managed a training team of 20 people to ensure protocol was met at every facet throughout new hire training.

Computer Specialist – 552nd CRS/AWACS/MSIMS – Tinker AFB, OK

2000 - 2003

Performed maintenance on three E-3 mission simulators to support Airborne Warning and Control System mission crew training. Troubleshot and repaired faulty data display systems, saving valuable man hours and an estimated \$385,000 (07.2002).

- VETERAN OF OPERATION ENDURING FREEDOM
- RECIPIENT OF AIR FORCE ACHIEVEMENT MEDAL